

Dr. Chentao Yang

| Göteborg, Sweden | +46 72 872 8542

www.cyang.pro

yangcht@gmail.com

github.com/yangcht

in www.linkedin.com/in/yangcht

Total citations: 1046 H-index: 19

As a trained astrophysicist, I have a solid foundation in math and physics. My hands-on experience in astrophysics has sharpened my data analysis skills and scientific exploration spirits. I'm naturally curious and versed in dissecting complex problems. This enables me to balance intricate details with big-picture perspectives.

PERSONAL

Date of birth May 1988 **Nationality** China

LANGUAGE

Mandarin **Native** Full proficiency **English French** Elementary **Swedish** Beginner **Spanish Beginner**

INTERESTS



Philosophy, Fiction, Science



Jazz, Classic, Soundtrack



Hiking, Citywalk



Sci-fi, Indie, Mystery

QUICK FACTS

50+ pulications in top international journals, **1000+** citations **5+** GitHub projects, **50+** stars (Bayesian/frequentist statistics, MCMC, graphic design)

12+ Oral presentations in international conferences (including invited) **500+** award PI observing telescope time from **30+** proposals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chalmers tekniska högskola (2021-current)

Postdoctral Researcher in astrophysics

- Analyzed large interferometric radio data sets of galaxies.
- Visualized images and related physical parameters.
- Quantified data and interpreted results via mathematical & physical models.
- Led international teams in conducting independent complete research projects.

European Southern Observatory, ESO (2017-2021) Joint ALMA Observatory (2017-2021)

Postdoctral Fellow in astrophysics

- Stationed at ESO Chile, a leading center for astronomical research.
- Astronomy duties at ALMA, the most advanced ground-based telescope.
- Independent research from ideas to publications.

EDUCATION

Université Paris-Saclay (2014-2017)

(Top 20 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

PhD in astrophysics

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (2013-2017)

(Top 70 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

PhD in astrophysics

Beijing Normal Univesity (2010-2013)

Master in astrophysics

Beijing Normal University (2006-2010)

Bachelor in astronomy

(Graduate with distinguished honour, all universities in Beijing)

SKILLS

Operating Systems: current OS





Shell (Unix/Linux), Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, ...) Languages:

Julia, IDL, FORTRAN, MATLAB

VS Code, Jupyter Lab, Git, Lagran, Adobe Illustrator, **Softwares:**

MS Office...

Teamwork Project management Attentiveness Problem-solving Data intuition Programming & Data Viz

AWARDS

Several Scholarships and Funding Awards

- Scholarship of National Astronomical Observatory of China
- National Undergraduate Innovative Test Program Grant (10k CNY)
- ESO Science Support Discretionary Fund (9k EUR)
- The LIA-Origins Short Visit Program Grant (3k EUR)

Fellowship

ESO Fellowship (Chile)